Okay, what up y'all? We're back with a
brand new video. Make sure you like and
subscribe if you appreciate the content.
Today we are uh showcasing the brand new
Ideogram 4 uh came out like last week
and um didn't come out last week. It was
already there, but they open sourced it.
So, essentially they released the
weights for everybody to use uh locally
on the computer and uh the model is
great. Uh I've seen a lot of people
complain about the model being censored
and [__] like that. It's not censored.
Um it's actually able to do a lot of
stuff out of the box that most models
are not able to do. Um essentially it's
going to do upper body stuff if you know
what I mean. And it's not going to do uh
down there pretty well just because it's
not trained on anything not safe for
work I understand. But aside from that,
the model is great. Um
you also need to use the prompting
method they uh said you need to use uh
because if you don't, you're actually
grieving and uh it's normal that you get
uh censored [__] errors and [__] like
that.
>> [snorts]
>> So, for this model you need to use uh
JSON prompting.
Uh this is a JSON prompt. This is what
it looks like. So, I'll just extend that
just a little bit.
So, if you go in there, I'll just do the
first one just so you kind of get an
idea. Um
everything is described um precisely
with bounding boxes. These are not
necessary, so you can run it without it.
But essentially it's giving uh the exact
position in the image for what you're
trying to make. So, it's basically you
can think of it as uh something like a
ControlNet but not really uh in the
sense that it's going to look at the
image, give you a precise um
coordinates, and then the model will be
able to generate what you said uh in the
exact spot you put it. So, it's super
nice for that. Uh it can do designs or
posters and [__] like that super well.
And uh obviously it can do, you know, AI
influencer stuff as well. Uh this is
based on this image here.
So, as you can see, the composition
looks kind of the same. Um I know the
the angle of the camera is not exactly
similar, but that's one of the better um
even with ControlNet I can't get
something that good usually with the
other models. Um so, yeah. Super good.
Uh here we can go to the next one, the
selfie. Um obviously this one has some
blurring into it, but aside from that,
the image is essentially the same. Um
there's an AI look to it. I'm not going
to say it doesn't have it. Uh but the
these are real images that off
Pinterest. So, I'm sure we can get
something even better if we do some free
up scaling. And also, this is only a 1
megapixel image, right? So, if we go to
2 megapixel, 4 megapixel, we'll be able
to get, you know, way better results.
But obviously, the higher you go,
the slower it's going to be. And I don't
want to wait like multiple minutes for
one image. So, I I keep it at one or
two. If I like the result, I just go
again with the same seed and
just up the resolution.
Let's go for the third image here. Boom.
This, [music] I mean, the composition is
a little bit different, obviously, but
it kind of got the photography style
pretty well.
>> [music]
>> Obviously, this is an edited image with
the There's a filter on it. And it kind
of got it. Even the pants do look
similar, which these are kind of hard to
do just cuz
different pants,
kind of unconventional types of pants.
But yeah, in general, I think that's
pretty good. It's not the best, but
obviously, if you run it at a higher res
and maybe change add something in the
prompts, you might be able to get
something a little bit better. And then
we have the final image, the selfie
shot.
Obviously,
the the positioning is pretty much the
same. It even got the the phone in the
same spot. It got the necklaces. It got
what else? The stars on the case as
well.
But it's not the best in the sense that
it doesn't really look like actual
selfie in the dirty mirror like this
one. But I'm sure this can be fixed
with, you know, better prompting and
[__] like that. So, it shouldn't be a
really that big of a deal. In general, I
think the model is quite good
at what it does.
So, I'll go over my pipeline for the
workflow and then I'll go in AI toolkit
for the lower training. So, yeah.
Here, this is the system prompt I use
for generating the actual prompts using
reference images. And here we have a
node I made using LM Studio on your
local computer.
So, yeah, kind of two options. If you
want to use LM Studio, I might be able
to share my node with my subscribers on
the school. So, just go there.
Your other options are to generate,
you know, actual prompts using like
something like Quest Studio or Gemini or
any free
LM that can watch images and generate
coordinates. Um, I I tried the quant 3.5
models for this and they don't work
properly. They give bogus um,
bogus coordinates and it kind of messes
up everything. But with the Gemma 4 26B
I use here, uh, as you can see we can
get pretty precise um,
uh, how do you call it? Pretty precise
bounding boxes in the prompts and
everything.
So, I really like that. Um, I think it's
like a super easy way. And then what you
can do is actually modify the bounding
boxes and then pass that prompt directly
in there so you can get exactly what you
want. And uh, yeah. So, I like it. Um,
uh, that's my pipeline. I'll share the
workflow but you'll need the node. Um,
if you don't want to use my pipeline you
can use the template um,
the template uh, for Ideogram uh,
directly in comfy. You just need to
update the latest version. Uh, you can
just grab this one here and click on it
and you'll be able to run the workflow
um, the way they said it should be run.
And yeah, um, that's pretty much it for
the pipeline for the settings and
everything. I mean there's nothing too
crazy here. Uh, it's mostly the original
workflow. Uh, but here we're going to
use a different uh, sampler. Uh, we used
the Hume. We used Hume here and uh, it
works super well and we changed uh, the
VAE to the small flux one. It's going to
take a little bit less memory. And uh,
here we have the LoRAs. Uh, you need to
plug uh, your LoRA directly in both
models or it's not going to work
properly. Uh, I did test that and that's
accurate.
And yeah, that's pretty much it for the
workflow. Nothing too crazy. Uh, there's
a couple of settings here for um, you
know, the quality. Um, I use the turbo
uh, but you can change the values in
there if you need to. Uh, it doesn't
have to be whatever that this is. Um,
I think the default one at 20 steps will
give you pretty good results most of the
time. Uh, so I would do the the best
results you'll get will be at 2
megapixels and 20 steps. Uh, after that
it kind of just doesn't really matter
anymore.
And uh, yeah. That's pretty much it for
the workflow. Now we're going to go in
AI toolkit and actually train that model
on our dataset. Uh, if you don't know
how to make a dataset join the school.
There's a bunch of stuff over there for
you to learn how to do that. And uh,
yeah, let's get it.
Okay, so we are on the RunPod right now.
Uh this is what we're going to use to
train the LoRA. Uh you can do this
locally with a 4090 or 5090. The process
is essentially the same. Uh I might make
another video specifically on how to do
it locally if there is any um ask for
that. But yeah, um I'll have my link in
the description to get free credits on
RunPod if it's your first time. Um so
yeah, first of all, we go to pods here,
okay? Uh we select the GPU. Uh you can
select a
5090, 4090, Pro 6000. These are going to
be uh the ones uh that will work the
best. Our Pro uh 4500 will work as well.
Uh actually, anything can work. It's
just going to be slower uh if you use,
you know, a low low-end GPU, right? Uh
you just need to have at least 24 gigs
of VRAM and you should be good. Uh so
here, I'll just choose uh the Pro 6000
here just because I can. You don't need
to use that, but I'm going to get it
done with it fast, so I'll just take the
best one. Uh here, yeah, AI Toolkit.
Select that.
Uh then for the container disk, we don't
use a network volume. We use a volume
disk here. And you can leave the uh the
storage as is or you can turn it down,
really. Uh doesn't really matter. Um
and then, uh you can deploy on demand.
Take that.
It's going to start uh the pod for you.
So, just refresh here.
And we have the pod here. So, it's going
to download everything it needs, and
uh
so you kind of just have to wait here.
And then you'll see uh in the connect
tab, uh HTTP service will pop up. You
open that up in a new tab. Boom. Uh AI
Toolkit, you add the password. The
password is password. And uh you're in,
okay? Then, first thing you need to do,
obviously, you need to add your data
set. Uh like I said before, if you don't
have a data set, I have many videos on
my school uh covering that part. Uh I'm
not going to be putting those on
YouTube. I can't reuse old videos, but
um everything is uploaded over there if
you've been following me uh before. So
here, new data set. Just name it.
Doesn't really matter the name.
And then you need to add your images in.
Uh I'll do that here. Just give me a
second.
Okay, so I added in my data set. This is
the face images.
Um
and after that is the body images.
Obviously, I'm not going to go too too
hard here, but uh yeah, we don't have
any captions for these images. We're
just going to train without captions,
[__] it, and we'll see what we get.
Obviously, um I know it works because I
did it, but um I'll just go ahead and do
a new job here. Uh we can call uh the
Laura whatever we need, so I'll call it
Laura uh ideal uh
V2, it's V2 for me, whatever.
Uh and then for the trigger word, I'll
just use uh
Laura ideal with a zero. And uh that's
it. Now,
for the model, we go ahead ideal RAM 4.
Uh I have a 3060 and I don't need low
VRAM. You can use it though if you want
to. Um and here we can leave everything
as is. Um we're just going to go save
every 150 and we keep um every single uh
checkpoint uh here.
Sorry. [clears throat] Um here we'll go
prodigy with a learning rate of one.
I've seen comments on my other videos
saying, "Why would you use a learning
rate of one? You don't know what you're
doing. You're just [__] [__] I'm
sorry." Um if you don't know what you're
talking about, just don't talk, bro. Um
here we use EMA and
we're not going to cache anything, we
don't need to.
Uh the Laura uh the data set is already
selected, that's good. And uh we don't
have a default caption, the default
caption is going to be the trigger word.
And uh yeah, uh we cache the latents. Um
the one um Laura results you saw in a
comfy UI, so this, this is trained at
512. And obviously,
um I believe if we train at higher
resolution, we can get, you know,
sharper results, but it really depends
on your data set at the end of the day.
So,
here we can I'll just train at 512, but
you can go way higher and it will give
you better results. I just don't want to
wait too long. The higher you go in res,
obviously, the longer it's going to take
to generate your image. So, yeah. Uh
here, uh these are uh captions. So,
I'll just use a caption I already did.
So, I'll just use this and that's going
to be the sample that's going to be
generated every
uh 150 steps here.
Um here, I want to go a little bit
lower. I don't need that many steps,
bro.
And then, um we can skip the first
sample, just save up on time.
Uh yeah, okay. So, let's say we're happy
with that. We can go ahead and create a
job like this.
But then, before that, we need to go
into settings.
And we need to open up Hugging Face.
Okay, Hugging Face.
You need to have an account. Then you
need to go in access tokens.
Boom.
And then you need to create a new token.
If you already have one, you can just
invalidate and refresh. Or if you don't
already have one, you create a new
token. You select everything on the
first part here. You give it a name.
Let's call it ideal. And then you just
create your token.
Then you can use this token in AI
Toolkit to actually get access to the
model. You also might need to go on the
Ideogram page workflow thing and ask for
access to the model. You'll have to do
that. If you don't do that, you're not
going to be able to train on it. That's
just how it is. That's not me. That's
just Ideogram that decided that. Okay?
Then we can go back in AI Toolkit and
you'll be pasting your
your access token directly in there.
Then you save.
And then we can go back to the queue.
Select this and start press play. That's
essentially going to start the training.
Going to download the models and
everything for you. And you kind of just
have to wait after that. So, yeah. Um
And then here you'll be seeing your
samples for your data set using the
prompt we added not too long ago. So,
that's basically it. Now we just wait
and I'll show you all the samples after.
Then we go back in ComfyUI, do a little
test run, and that's going to be it.
Let's get it.
>> Okay, so we are at about 600, 700 steps.
Already started kind of downloading the
checkpoints.
This is what This is 150. That's 300.
That's 450. That's 600. Um here we can
see 600 does have the likeness already.
But if you actually go ahead and test
the prior versions. So, here I tested
the 450 and this is what we got out of
it.
Here. So, the lightness is already there
at 450.
Um
right? It's already there. Like, that's
that's my character.
Um so, we could go 600, 750, maybe. But,
we don't want to over train. So, I'm
happy with 450, honestly.
Uh but, I can try 600, as well, just so
we can see. But, that's pretty much
done.
Um and the results are I mean, you you
guys be the judge, I guess. But, I think
the results are absolutely fine. Uh so,
yeah.
Uh
the results are going to be extremely
similar to my prior Laura because it's
exactly the same data set with the exact
same settings. So, I would not expect it
to be that much different.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh but, yeah. Um pretty happy with it.
Uh let's try 600, and that's going to be
the video.
So, we just go into AI Tool Kit. We uh
download uh this uh 600 and 750, might
as well.
Um you know, you don't need to do the
whole 3,000 steps. It's going to cost
you a lot of money, and you're not even
going to use the last checkpoint. So, I
would say around 600, 750,
you can stop it. Um and test it out in
actually ComfyUI, not with the samples.
And if you're happy with what you got,
you can go ahead and just stop the
training there and save a a lot of
money, right?
So, yeah. Um
I downloaded those. So, let me just put
them in the right folder here.
Boom. Boom.
And then, we refresh.
We can go here.
And select 600.
Then, run it.
Let's see.
Okay. I'll just skip to when it's done.
I'm not going to be making you wait
here.
Okay, so we are done with the
generation. So,
damn, I [__] hate
this [__] man. Jesus.
Okay, let's see here. So, this is the
600 checkpoint. Um
I mean, these are pretty good, no? I
think it's pretty good. Honestly.
And then we have the kind of the dirty
mirror reflection here. It looks pretty
good.
But, in general,
I mean, the likeness is obviously there.
It's not really up for debate at this
point. So, yeah. Uh that's pretty much
it. I'm going to stop there. I don't
want to yap too much. Uh if you want
more information, you can join the
Discord, join the school. Uh we are
almost at 1,000 people on school, so
that's pretty nice. And
uh yeah. Um
you can grab the workflow over there, as
well. That's going to be it. I'll see
you in the next one. Peace.